https://www.ontariolearn.com/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
OntarioLearn Online Collaborative Inc. (“OntarioLearn”) has developed policies and procedures (the “Privacy Policy”) to protect our website users’ personal information and to ensure that OntarioLearn complies with current applicable privacy legislation.
OntarioLearn reserves the right to change the Privacy Policy at any time. As a result, OntarioLearn requests that you, as a website user (“you”), read this section from time to time in order to be informed of possible changes in the OntarioLearn Privacy Policy. If the Privacy Policy changes, and personal information is collected for a purpose that is different from that stated at the time that it was originally collected, the Privacy Policy will be modified and updated as necessary. Changes to the Privacy Policy will take effect on the 31st day from the date the updated Privacy Policy is posted. In addition to modifying the date, OntarioLearn will post all updates to the Privacy Policy on the “Privacy Policy” page of www.ontariolearn.com (the “Website”).
TYPE OF INFORMATION COLLECTED
OntarioLearn may collect personal information from you when you create an account in, or submit information to, the Website like your name, e-mail address, phone number or IP address.
You may consent to the use of personal information and you may withdraw consent to the use of this information (excluding such information which may be legally retained indefinitely and such information which is maintained in anonymized aggregate form by OntarioLearn) at any time (subject to reasonable notice and the legal obligations OntarioLearn is subject to).  If no explicit consent is provided, your consent is implied.  You may withdraw consent by contacting OntarioLearn at the contact information provided on the About page (Contact Us section) of the Website. Please note that withdrawing consent may result in a reduction in access to the Website and to specific features of the Website.
Additionally, please note that OntarioLearn may aggregate the data (including personal information) it collects and, by disclosing your personal information on this Website, you hereby agree and consent to the OntarioLearn collection, use and disclosure of such data in aggregate anonymized form among related and OntarioLearn Member Institutions (“Members”).
USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
OntarioLearn and Members may use the personal information collected by them from you for the following reasons: to communicate with you and/or deliver information and services to you regarding the work of OntarioLearn or Members; or to process course evaluations as part of our quality assessment process.
USE OF COOKIES
When you navigate the Website, small files called ‘cookies’ may be attached to your web browser. These files identify your web browser and save information such as passwords so that websites can recognize you.  You can set your browser to disable cookies, but some websites may not work properly if you do this.
OntarioLearn uses the following types of cookies:
Session cookies – These are used as an integral part of the identification process for some of the OntarioLearn online applications. This is for security purposes to determine that you are who you say you are and to provide you with your confidential account information during an online session. No personal information is kept in session cookies and they are stored only in your browser’s temporary (cache) memory. When you log out of your session, the cookie is no longer valid and is discarded when you close your browser.
Persistent cookies – These are more permanent and can be re-read when you return to the site that placed them on your computer. The information in them is written onto your hard drive and remains there until the expiry date of the cookie. They are used to identify and provide personalized features (for example, to help OntarioLearn remember which official language you prefer) and for tracking traffic patterns to and from the Website.
OntarioLearn may also use Google Analytics. Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc., helps to measure traffic patterns to, from, and within the Website and uses cookies to collect aggregated information about you. Information collected by Google Analytics is stored on Google servers in the United States and may be subject to the governing legislation in that country (for example, the USA Patriot Act). Your IP address is anonymized prior to being stored on Google’s servers in order to help safeguard your privacy. For further information about Google Analytics, please refer to http://www.google.com/intl/en_ALL/policies/privacy/.
If you wish, you may opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics by disabling or refusing the cookies; by disabling JavaScript within your browser; or by using https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en. Disabling Google Analytics or JavaScript will still permit you to access comparable information or services from the Website.
DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
Under no circumstances will your personal information, which OntarioLearn collects, be communicated or disseminated to third parties, except as provided herein or unless this is necessary to carry out the services you request on the Website.
You agree and acknowledge that the personal information which you submit on the website and which is collected by OntarioLearn may be transferred outside of Canada and, if you are resident in the UK, the personal data may be transferred outside the European Economic Area.
In the normal course of business, OntarioLearn may disclose some personal information to third party service providers and suppliers as needed, and also to Google Analytics, which is used to generate detailed statistics about the Website’s traffic and traffic sources.
OntarioLearn must also disclose personal information when required by law to do so. For example, if OntarioLearn is presented with a search warrant or other legal order or if personal information is requested from an investigative body in relation to a breach of the law, personal information may be disclosed.
PROTECTION OF PRIVACY AND PERSONAL INFORMATION
Personal information will be processed by persons in charge of the processing for the purposes described above. In particular, these persons will record, organize, keep, elaborate, modify, select, and use or delete personal data for operations necessary to carry out the purposes for which you have given your consent. In the context of this Website, the processing of personal information will be performed by OntarioLearn and will be carried out using both paper and electronic tools. OntarioLearn is committed to ensuring that your personal information is secure and kept confidential. OntarioLearn will disclose breaches of your personal information as required by applicable law.
RETENTION OF INFORMATION
OntarioLearn will retain personal information linked to a particular course for up to thirty one (31) days following the end of that course, or longer as required by law, after which time the information will be deleted and destroyed.
For further information on the OntarioLearn Privacy Policy, please contact the OntarioLearn Privacy Officer, Interim-Executive Director, Susan Savoie (Graham), at our e-mail address found on the About page (Contact us) section of the Website or by email susan@ontariolearn.com.
Return to the homepage
AboutStudent ServicesCollegesProgramsCoursesStarting Out
RegisterHelpLog In
Français
BylawsPolicies & ProceduresPrivacyLegalAccessibility
Funded by :
Copyright ©OntarioLearn 2016
